DONGDONG YUE (1994-01)

(+86) 131-8293-1727 · yued@seu.edu.cn

Contact Address:

Dongdong Yue Postdoctoral researcher School of Mathematics 503-2, Southeast University SEU Road 2, Nanjing 210096, China 13182931727



2011.9 - 2015.6

BIOGRAPHY

Dongdong Yue received the B.S. degree in applied mathematics from Hefei University of Technology, Hefei, China, in 2015, and the Ph.D. Degree in control science and engineering from Southeast University, Nanjing, China, in 2021. Since 2021 July, he has been a postdoctoral researcher with the School of Mathematics, Southeast University. From May to August 2019, he visited the Control and Robotics Lab, Okayama Prefectural University, Japan. From October 2019 to October 2020, he visited the Delft Center for System and Control, Delft University of Technology, The Netherlands. His research interests include adaptive control, distributed optimization and neural networks. Dr. Yue, as the first author, has published several papers in leading journals and conferences, and has received the Best Paper in Theory Award from the 18th IEEE International Conference on Networking, Sensing, and Control.

Hefei University of Technology (HFUT), B. Sc., Math and Applied Mathematics

EDUCATION

Southeast University (SEU), Master student, Applied Mathematics	2015.9 - 2017.1
Supervisor: Prof. Jinde Cao	
Southeast University, Ph. D., Control Science and Engineering	2017.3 - 2021.3
Supervisor: Prof. Qi Li, Prof. Jinde Cao; Thesis: Distributed adaptive control of uncertain network systems	
RESEARCH EXPERIENCES	
SciYon Automation Group Co.,Ltd. (Nanjing), Intern Engineer	2017.8 - 2019.4
Okayama Prefectural University (OPU, Japan), Xin Lab, Visiting Researcher	2019.5 - 2019.8
Host: Prof. Xin Xin	
Delft University of Technology (TUD, The Netherlands), DCSC, Joint Ph. D.	2019.10 - 2020.10
Supervisor: Prof. Bart De Schutter, Prof. Simone Baldi	
Southeast University (SEU), School of Mathematis, Postdoc	2021.7 -
Supervisor: Prof. Jinde Cao	

PUBLICATIONS

Journal papers

- [1]. **Dongdong Yue**, Simone Baldi, Jinde Cao, and Bart De Schutter. Distributed adaptive optimization with weight-balancing. *IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control*, 67(4): 2068-2075, 2022. (IF: 5.792)
- [2]. **Dongdong Yue**, Simone Baldi, Jinde Cao, Qi Li, and Bart De Schutter. A directed spanning tree adaptive control solution to time-varying formations. *IEEE Transactions on Control of Network Systems*, 8(2): 690-701, 2021. (IF: 3.502)
- [3]. **Dongdong Yue**, Jinde Cao, Qi Li, and Qingshan Liu. Neural-network-based fully distributed adaptive consensus for a class of uncertain multiagent systems. *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems*, 32(7): 2965-2977, 2021. (IF: 10.451)
- [4]. **Dongdong Yue**, Qi Li, Kil To Chong, and Jinde Cao. Neural-network-embedded distributed average tracking of agents with matching unknown nonlinearities. *Asian Journal of Control*, 23(6): 2628-2641, 2021. (IF: 3.452)

- [5]. **Dongdong Yue**, Jinde Cao, Qi Li, and Mahmoud Abdel-Aty. Distributed neuro-adaptive formation control for uncertain multi-agent systems: node- and edge-based designs. *IEEE Transactions on Network Science and Engineering*, 7(4): 2656-2666, 2020. (IF: 3.894)
- [6]. **Dongdong Yue**, Jinde Cao, Qi Li, and Xinli Shi. Neuro-adaptive consensus strategy for a class of nonlinear time-delay multi-agent systems with an unmeasurable high-dimensional leader. *IET Control Theory & Applications*, 13(2): 230-238, 2019. (IF: 3.343)

Conferences papers

- [1]. **Dongdong Yue**, Simone Baldi, and Jinde Cao, "Distributed Adaptive Consensus Disturbance Rejection: a Directed-spanning-tree Perspective," *Chinese Control Conference (CCC)*, Hefei, China, 2022. (EI)
- [2]. **Dongdong Yue**, Simone Baldi, and Jinde Cao, "Robust Model Reference Adaptive Consensus with Neural Networks," *Chinese Control and Decision Conference (CCDC)*, Hefei, China, 2022. (EI)
- [3]. **Dongdong Yue**, Simone Baldi, Wenying Xu and Jinde Cao, "Distributed adaptive consensus via event-triggered sampling: an edge-based method," *IEEE International Conference on Networking, Sensing and Control (ICNSC)*, Xiamen, China, 2021. (EI)
- [4]. **Dongdong Yue**, Qi Li, Jinde Cao, and Xuegang Tan. Robust neuro-adaptive asymptotic consensus for a class of uncertain multi-agent systems: an edge-based paradigm. *International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)*, Budapest, Hungary, 2019. (EI)
- [5]. Xuegang Tan, Jinde Cao, Rensi Chen, and **Dongdong Yue**. The event-based consensus of multi-agent networks with control gain in normal distribution. *Chinese Control Conference (CCC)*, Guangzhou, China, 2019. (EI)

PROJECTS

- Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities under Grant 3207012201A4, 2022.7-2024.12, Distributed adaptive optimization and economic dispatch with bound constraints
- China Postdoctoral Science Foundation under Grant BX2021064, 2021.7-2023.7, Distributed adaptive optimization and economic dispatch
- Graduate Research and Innovation Program of Jiangsu Province under Grant KYCX19_0086, 2019.3-2020.3, Distributed adaptive control of uncertain network systems

Honors

- Outstanding graduates of Class 2015, HFUT (2015.7)
- National Government Scholarship for Studying Abroad, CSC (2019.5)
- Education Foundation Scholarship, SEU (2019.8)
- National Government Scholarship for Ph. D. students (2020.12)
- Best Paper in Theory, ICNSC2021 (2021.12)
- Outstanding PhD thesis of Class of 2022, SEU (2022.6)

EXTRA

- Member of IEEE since 2021.9, Member of CAA since 2022.1, Member of CICC since 2022.3.
- Reviewers of journals including IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics, Applied Mathematics and Mechanics, etc.
- Reviewers of conferences including CAC2021, ICACI2021, etc.